let basicQuestions = [
    {
    question: "Which creature in Greek mythology was half-man and half-bull?",
    options:["Minotaur", "Centaur", "Faun"],
    correctAnswer: "Minotaur"
    },
    {
    question: "Olympians were cinsidered to be the major gods among greek mythology, how many where they?",
    options: ["6", "16", "12"],
    correctAnswer: "12"
    },
    {
    question: "Who was the beautiful youth that Greek goddess Aphrodite loved?",
    options: ["Eros", "Adonis", "Ganymede"],
    correctAnswer: "Adonis"
    },
    {
    question: "Which one of the following was both God of the Underworld and God of the Dead?",
    options: ["Hephaestus", "Hades", "Poseidon"],
    correctAnswer: "Hades"
    },
    {
    question: "Who was the god of love and love, lust, beauty, pleasure, passion,",
    options: ["Hera", "Aphrodite", "Athena"],
    correctAnswer: "Aphrodite"
    },
    {
    question: "Who was the god of war and courage, but also personifies brutality and bloodlust?",
    options: ["Athena", "Ares", "Kratos"],
    correctAnswer: "Ares"
    },
    {
    question: `Artemis is greek goddess of what – only one among all gods?`,
    options: ["Harvest and agriculture", "Virginity and chastity", "Hunt and music"],
    correctAnswer: "Virginity and chastity"
    }
];

let moderateQuestions = [
    {
    question: "According to legend, who fired the arrow that hit Achilles in the heel, his only vulnerable spot?",
    options:["Paris", "Hermes", "His mother"],
    correctAnswer: "Paris"
    },
    {
    question: "Who was the mythical Greek hunter after whom a constellation is named?",
    options: ["Orion", "Pleiades", "Ursa Major"],
    correctAnswer: "Orion"
    },
    {
    question: "What did Daedalus construct for King Minos so that he could keep the Minotaur there?",
    options: ["Golden Cage", "Labyrinth", "A walled enclosure"],
    correctAnswer: "Labyrinth"
    },
    {
    question: `Whose son is Phaeton, who attempt to drive his father’s chariot, but is killed by a thunderbolt from Zeus?`,
    options: ["Hephaestus", "Apollo", "Hermes"],
    correctAnswer: "Apollo"
    },
    {
    question: "In Greek mythology, who was the goddess of the rainbow? ",
    options: ["Hebe", "Iris", "Electra"],
    correctAnswer: "Iris"
    },
    {
    question: "Artemis is greek goddess of what, only one among all gods?",
    options: ["Harvest and agriculture", "Virginity and chastity", "Hunt and music"],
    correctAnswer: "Virginity and chastity"
    },
    {
    question: "Who were the guardian spirits of nature in Greek mythology?",
    options: ["Muses", "Nymphs", "Titans"],
    correctAnswer: "Nymphs"
    }
];

let challengingQuestions= [
    {
    question: `What was left in Pandora’s box after she released misery and evil?`,
    options:["Hope", "Wisdom", "Courage"],
    correctAnswer: "Hope"
    },
    {
    question:"Orpheus went into the underworld to rescue who?",
    options: ["Eurydice", "Persephone", "Aphrodite"],
    correctAnswer: "Eurydice"
    },
    {
    question: "Who fell in love with a statue he had carved?",
    options: ["Pygmalion", "Prometheus", "King Midas"],
    correctAnswer: "Pygmalion"
    },
    {
    question: "In greek mythology clio was the muse of what?",
    options: ["Poetry", "Dance", "History"],
    correctAnswer: "History"
    },
    {
    question: "Who was the titan who famously devoured his children, also the father of Zeus?",
    options: ["Cronus", "Uranus", "Pontus"],
    correctAnswer: "Cronus"
    },
    {
    question: "Parnassus was the sacred mountain home of the muses and which Greek god?",
    options: ["Athena", "Hephaistus", "Apollo"],
    correctAnswer: "Apollo"
    },
    {
    question: "Who were Erybus, the darkness and Nyx, the night?",
    options: ["First two creations born out of chaos", "Deities that were released from Pandoras box", "Children of Gaia"],
    correctAnswer: "First two creations born out of chaos"
    }
];
